<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- SPDX-License-Identifier: GPL-3.0-only -->
<resources>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_title">CipherBoard</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_vault_locked">Vault locked</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_vault_locked_description">Unlock to access your local identity and paired contacts.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_unlock_failed">The Vault could not be unlocked. Check the device lock and try again.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_unlock_cancelled">Vault unlock was cancelled.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_key_invalidated">The Android Keystore key is no longer valid. Existing protected data cannot be opened; pairing must be set up again after a safe reset.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_reset_action">Reset inaccessible Vault</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_reset_title">Reset local identity and contacts?</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_reset_warning">The old identity, contacts, sessions, pending messages, and replay records will be permanently deleted. Contacts on other devices will not trust the new identity. Pair with every contact again and compare the new Safety Number.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_reset_confirm">Delete and reset</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_reset_failed">The inaccessible Vault could not be fully reset. No new identity was created. Restart CipherBoard and try again.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_device_lock_required">Set a secure device PIN or password before creating the Vault.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_create_identity">Create your local identity</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_create_identity_description">CipherBoard creates the cryptographic identity on this device. No account, phone number, email, or network connection is used. Clearing app data changes this identity and requires pairing again.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_local_name">Your local name</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_local_name_private">This name stays on this device and is not part of your cryptographic identity.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_local_name_required">Enter a local name.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_identity_failed">The local identity could not be created. Check the name and try again.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_create">Create identity</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_vault_read_failed">Protected local data could not be read safely.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_pairing_unavailable">Contact pairing is not available right now.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_identity_local">Local cryptographic identity</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_fingerprint">Identity fingerprint</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_vault_unlocked">Vault unlocked</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_vault_unlocked_level">Vault unlocked · Keystore: %1$s</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_keystore_strongbox">StrongBox</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_keystore_tee">trusted execution environment</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_keystore_software">software-backed</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_keystore_unknown">unknown security level</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_contacts">Contacts</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_add_contact">Add contact</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_no_contacts">No paired contacts yet. Add a contact and complete the two-way QR scan in person.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_keyboard_settings">Keyboard settings</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_security">Security</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_licenses">Licenses and source</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_lock_vault">Lock Vault</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_status_verified">Verified</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_status_unverified">Unverified</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_status_key_changed">Key changed · pairing required</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_status_pairing_required">Pairing required</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_home_status_session_error">Session error · pair again</string>

    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_title">Licenses and source</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_source_notice">CipherBoard is an unofficial modified HeliBoard distribution. These documents are available offline. The exact corresponding source is distributed as a versioned source archive alongside the release APK; BUILD_INFO identifies its Git commit.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_gpl">GNU GPLv3</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_inventory">License inventory</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_notices">Third-party notices</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_upstream">HeliBoard upstream record</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_apache">Apache License 2.0</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_blue_oak">Blue Oak Model License 1.0.0</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_bsd">BSD-3-Clause notices</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_cc">Creative Commons BY-SA 4.0</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_licenses_read_failed">This bundled license document could not be read.</string>

    <string name="cipherboard_security_title">Security</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_intro">CipherBoard reduces specific risks by encrypting messages before they reach an SMS, messenger, or email app. It does not eliminate every way a message or device can be compromised.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_pairing_warning">Sender identity is trusted only after both people compare the Safety Number during the in-person QR pairing and mark the contact as verified.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_protects_title">What CipherBoard is designed to protect</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_protect_transport">Carriers, messenger services, email providers, and compromised transport accounts receive ciphertext instead of message text.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_protect_integrity">Authenticated encryption detects changed or forged messages. Persisted ratchet state rejects replay and supports bounded out-of-order delivery.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_protect_storage">Identity and session records are encrypted under a user-authenticated, non-exportable Android Keystore key. StrongBox is attempted first, with a TEE fallback.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_protect_plaintext">Secure composer text is not committed to the external app, clipboard, keyboard learning, logs, notifications, or plaintext history. Protected message windows block normal screenshots and recent-app previews.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_protect_offline">The runtime has no Internet permission, uses no server or cloud account, and excludes protected data from Android backup and device transfer.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limits_title">What CipherBoard cannot fully protect against</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_unlocked_device">An attacker controlling an unlocked device or reading its live screen.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_os">Root access, kernel or operating-system exploits, compromised firmware, or a faulty Keystore or StrongBox implementation.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_apk">A malicious or substituted CipherBoard APK, a compromised build toolchain, or a stolen signing key.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_observation">A camera recording the screen or another person reading over your shoulder. Screenshot blocking is not an absolute screen-capture guarantee.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_accessibility">Malicious Accessibility, screen-reader, input, device-admin, or similarly privileged services.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_metadata">Traffic analysis and metadata exposed to the transport, including who communicated, when, and approximate message size.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_coercion">Physical coercion or disclosure of the device PIN, password, or biometric access.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_limit_defects">Defects in the cryptographic library, Android integration, parser, storage, pairing flow, or user interface.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_audit_notice">CipherBoard uses established cryptographic primitives, but the complete product has not undergone an independent security audit.</string>
    <string name="cipherboard_security_high_risk">Before high-risk use, verify the APK signing certificate and SHA-256 from a trusted source, keep verified boot and the bootloader locked, use a strong device PIN or password, disable untrusted Accessibility services, compare every Safety Number in person, and obtain an independent applied-cryptography and Android security review.</string>
</resources>
